Diana Ross is Billie Holiday. Diana Ross sings
Billie Holiday. And a superstar is born.
Lady Sings the Blues is a drama, music film directed by Sidney J. Furie.
Chronicles the rise and fall of legendary blues singer Billie
Holiday, beginning with her traumatic youth.
The story depicts her early attempts at a singing career and her eventual rise to stardom, as
well as her difficult relationship with Louis McKay, her boyfriend and manager.
Casting a shadow over even Holiday's brightest moments is the vocalist's severe
drug addiction, which threatens to end both her career and her life.
Billie Holiday, played by Diana Ross.
Louis McKay, played by Billy Dee Williams.
Piano Man, played by Richard Pryor.
Reg Hanley, played by James T. Callahan.
Harry, played by Paul Hampton.
Jerry, played by Sid Melton.
Lady Sings the Blues is a 1972 American biographical
musical drama film directed by Sidney J.
Furie about jazz singer Billie Holiday, loosely based on her 1956
autobiography that, in turn, took its title from Holiday's song.
It is produced by Motown Productions for Paramount Pictures.
Diana Ross, in her feature film debut, portrays Holiday, alongside a cast
that includes Billy Dee Williams, Richard Pryor, James T.
Callahan and Scatman Crothers.
The film was nominated for five Academy Awards in 1973,
including Best Actress for Diana Ross.
The film explores themes of new york city, brothel, jazz
singer or musician, mental breakdown, biography.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.